All right. In the last video, we showed
you how to use substr
um to pull text out of another piece of
text. But in order to do that, I had to
count out to find where this Wayne is.
That's really frustrating. So there is
an easier way to do that and I'm going
to show you how to do that.
So there is a function in JavaScript
called search. So, um if we want to do
this, we would say my text search
and it says
um it searches for something within a
string. So, we need to give it a symbol
to search through or we could hit the
down arrow and it says it just needs a
string and then it'll return a number.
So remember when I was counting this
out, I said that the B was at the zero
position and the R was at the one
position and so on and so forth. What
the search does is it says look through
a piece of string and see if it contains
another string and if it does give back
the position of that string. So if I was
looking for this W here, I could say
search for the W. And what I'm going to
do is I'm going to alert this to show
you what it does. So, I'm going to say
alert my text.arch
open quotes w close quote. And then I'm
going to close off both functions. Going
to save this and I'm going to open it
up. And it says it is in the sixth
position. So now without knowing where
Wayne was or having to count it out, I
now know it's in the sixth position. Um,
this could be a basic string. Um, or it
could be a more complicated string. Um,
so let's say I want to search for the
text of is. If I save that and I reload,
it says the text of is starts at the
12th position. So that means the letter
I is in the 12th position and the letter
S is in the 13th position. Um, which
makes sense because we knew that the B
from previous video was the 15th
position. So the space was the 14, the S
is the 13, and the I is the 12th
position. So using this my text.arch, we
were able to find the position of
something. So if I added a whole bunch
of text here and added a whole bunch of
text there,
I could find and pull out this Batman by
combining what I you what I just learned
with my substring substr function. So I
could say
let
Batman position equal my text.
And I'm going to search for the text
Batman.
Now I know that Batman is in here. I am
not going to count out the letters to
figure out where that is. But I do know
that Batman is six characters. So what I
can do is I can say let um Batman text
equal and then I'm going to say my text
dot and then I'm going to use the substr
function. It needs a starting position
and a length. So what I'm going to do is
I'm going to give it the Batman position
that we just found in the last one
because that gives back the number where
Batman starts.
And then I know that Batman is six
characters. So, that'll go six
characters over. And that should find us
the Batman text. Just to prove it, let's
do an alert. Batman text.
And we'll save it. And now, if we come
over and reload our page, we get the
text Batman. I have no idea where the B
is. I just smashed random characters
into this sentence. So, I have no idea
where the B for Batman is. But, I was
able to use the search function to find
out which position that's in. And then I
took that position and said move over
six positions. So one, two, three, four,
five, six. And then that grabbed the
entirety of Batman. And then I was able
to alert it. And so that is how you
would use the search function. Let's try
and search for something that's not in
there. And I will show you what the
search function gives you if it's not in
there. So let's do alert Batman
position. If we save it right now,
Batman is in there. So if we save it and
we come over, Batman starts in the 41st
position.
Let's search for something that's not in
there. Let's search for Superman. If we
save that and we come over to our
website, it gives us negative one. So if
zero is the start of the sentence,
negative one is outside of the sentence.
Or in other words, Superman is not in
this sentence. And that's how you use
search to determine if a string is
within another string.